<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Copyright 2013, by the California Institute of Technology. -->
<!-- ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged. -->
<!--  -->
<!-- $Id: $ -->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
   <properties>
      <title>Release Description 5.0.0a</title>
      <author>T. Huang</author>
   </properties>
   <body>
      <section name="Release Description 5.0.0a">
         <p>This release of the Ingest Program Set is a component of the integrated release (<a
               href="../../cm/release/index-5.0.0a.html">5.0.0a</a>) of the HORIZON System. This
            release is intended as an operational release.</p>
         <p>Building on capabilities delivered in the last release, this release focuses on
            improving the overall reliability of the Ingest System. Details on this release can be
            found in the following sections of this document:</p>
         <ul>
            <li><a href="#Capabilities">Capabilities</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Installation">Installation</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Operation">Operation</a></li>
         </ul>
      </section>
      <section name="Capabilities" id="Capabilities">
         <p>This section details the new, modified and corrected capabilities that comprise this
            release of the Ingest Program Set. In lieu of listing the capabilities by requirement
            they have been summarized. For a complete list of the requirements and their support
            status, see <a href="#Appendix_A_-_Requirements_Support">Appendix A</a>.</p>
         <subsection name="New Capabilities">
            <ul>
               <li>ingest client now supports local data repository created by data handlers for SIP
                  submission and monitoring.</li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Modified Capabilities">
            <ul>
               <li>Upgraded to build with Java 7</li>
               <li>Upgraded to build with Groovy 2.0.8</li>
               <li>Updated to support new SIP message protocol</li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Corrected Capabilities">
            <ul>
               <li>NONE</li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>
      </section>
      <section name="Installation" id="Installation">
         <p>This section details the procedures for installing and configuring the software in this
            program set.</p>
         <subsection name="Ingest-Server Installation">
            <p>The Ingest Server module consists of the core implementation for the program set
               (everything happens here). The installation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../ingest-server/install/index.html">Ingest Server Installation</a>
               document.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Ingest-Client Installation">
            <p>The Ingest Client module consists of command-line applications for interfacing with
               the Manager Web Service. The installation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../ingest-client/install/index.html">Ingest Client Installation</a>
               document.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
      <section name="Operation">
         <p>This section details any necessary setup and the commands for running the software in
            this program set.</p>
         <subsection name="Ingest-Server Operation">
            <p>The operation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../ingest-server/operate/index.html">Ingest Server Operation</a>
               document.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Ingest-Client Operation">
            <p>The operation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../ingest-client/operate/index.html">Ingest Client Operation</a>
               document.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
