<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Copyright 2007-2008, by the California Institute of Technology. -->
<!-- ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged. -->
<!--  -->
<!-- $Id: $ -->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
   <properties>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <author>T. Huang</author>
   </properties>
   <body>
      <section name="Installation">
         <p>This document describes how to install and configure the Ingest Engine. The following
            sections can be found in this document:</p>
         <ul>
            <li><a href="#Distribution_Contents">Distribution Contents</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Server_Configuration">Server Configuration</a></li>
         </ul>
      </section>
      <section name="Distribution Contents" id="Distribution_Contents">
         <p>This release of HORIZON's Ingest server requires Java Standard Edition
               1.8 or higher. The software is shipped in a self-contained GZIP file. Below is an
            illustration of the software distribution after it has been expanded:</p>
         <img src="../images/horizon_server_dist.jpg" alt=""/>
         <ul>
            <li><i>config</i> - this directory contains server configuration information.<ul>
                  <li><i>hroizonconfig.pm</i> - this is a Perl application launcher utility file. In
                     general the user/admin won't have to modify this file </li>
                  <li><i>HORIZONdomain.xml</i> - the domain file the software will use to establish
                     connection to the Ingest Grails middleware.</li>
                  <li><i>HORIZONserver.lcf</i> - the server log configuration file.</li>
               </ul></li>
            <li><i>lib</i> - this directory contains all run-time libraries for both client and
               server applications.</li>
            <li><i>sbin</i> - this directory contains launchers and/or utility program for the
               Ingest engine.</li>
            <li><i>useHORIZON.csh</i> - this file is a script for setting up the environment.</li>
         </ul>
      </section>
      <section name="Server Configuration" id="Server_Configuration">
         <p>Beginning with Version 4.0, HORIZON's Ingest server will no longer issue a boot request to the
            Middleware for its runtime configuration. The only configuration information required
            for the HORIZON's Ingest server to boot is the domain file and the log configuration file.</p>
         <subsection name="Logger">
            <p>The HORIZON's Ingest server was developed to use the popular message logging toolkit, <a
                  class="externalLink" href="http://logging.apache.org">log4j</a>, for flexible
               message filtering and redirection. Message logging level is used for message
               verbosity. Log4j supports the following levels - TRACE, DEBUG, INFO, WARN, ERROR, and
               FATAL. If the logger is configured for DEBUG level, the server will output messages
               that are logged in DEBUG..FATAL level and ignore all messages logged with TRACE
               level. By default, the server is shipped with INFO level enabled. For higher
               visibility into the operations within the server, the administrator can change the
               logging level to DEBUG in <i>config/HORIZONserver.lcf</i> as follows:</p>
            <source>
&lt;root&gt;
     &lt;level value=&quot;DEBUG&quot;/&gt;
     &lt;appender-ref ref=&quot;FILE&quot;/&gt;
     &lt;appender-ref ref=&quot;CONSOLE&quot;/&gt;
 &lt;/root&gt;
            </source>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Regarding the HORIZONdomain.xml file">
            <p>The domain file contains connection lookup information. It is a simple federation to
               URL mapping file. Ingest client uses this file to lookup the federation connection
               string.</p>
            <source>
&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot; ?&gt;
&lt;domain xmlns=&quot;http://horizon.jpl.nasa.gov&quot;&gt;
   &lt;default&gt;horizonDev&lt;/default&gt;
   &lt;federation&gt;
      &lt;name&gt;horizonDev&lt;/name&gt;
      &lt;url&gt;http://lanina.jpl.nasa.gov:8080/manager/ingest&lt;/url&gt;
   &lt;/federation&gt;
   &lt;sigevent&gt;http://lanina.jpl.nasa.gov:8080/sigevent&lt;/sigevent&gt;
   &lt;jobkeeper&gt;
      &lt;server&gt;lapinta:2181&lt;/server&gt;
      &lt;webservice&gt;lapinta:9998&lt;/webservice&gt;
   &lt;/jobkeeper&gt;
   &lt;discovery&gt;http://seastorm.jpl.nasa.gov:8983/solr.war&lt;/discovery&gt;
   &lt;inventory&gt;http://lanina.jpl.nasa.gov:9191&lt;/inventory&gt;
&lt;/domain&gt;
            </source>
            <p>It is recommended that you use the domain file generated from the Operator Tool since
               it will contain the URL values needed by the Ingest Server, namely, sigevent and
               jobkeeper.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Regarding the useHORIZON.csh script">
            <p>The <i>useHORIZON.csh</i> is an environment setting script.</p>
            <source>% cat useHORIZON.csh

setenv JAVA_HOME /usr/local/java
setenv PATH {JAVA_HOME}/bin:${PATH}

setenv HORIZON ${cwd}/config
setenv PATH ${HORIZON}/../sbin:${PATH}</source>
            <p>The script assumes your Java distribution is installed under <i>/user/local/java</i>.
               The script also assumes the user is sourcing it within the Ingest distribution
               directory. For multi-user operation environment, the line below should be modified
               with the correct directory path.</p>
            <source>setenv HORIZON &lt;path to the ingest server software distribution&gt;/config</source>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Regarding security at startup">
            <p>The HORIZON's Ingest server requires authentication with the HORIZON Middleware at startup time.
               Authentication requires username/password combination where the username must be
               registered as an administrator in the HORIZON Middleware. The authentication information
               can be provided at the HORIZON's Ingest server startup command arguments, or via the keychain
               file created by the HORIZON Client distribution (e.g. % ingest login).</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
