<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Copyright 2008, by the California Institute of Technology. -->
<!-- ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged. -->
<!--  -->
<!-- $Id: $ -->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
   <properties>
      <title>Compilation</title>
      <author>T. Huang</author>
   </properties>
   <body>
      <section name="Compilation">
         <p>This document describes how to setup and build the Security API program set. The
            following sections can be found in this document:</p>
         <ul>
            <li><a href="#Setup">Setup</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Build">Build</a></li>
         </ul>
         <p>This document assumes that the Security-API program set source tree has already been
            checked out to the local environment. See the <a class="externalLink"
               href="https://horizon/docs/horizon/cm/subversion/index.html">Using Subversion</a> document
            for details regarding the use of Subversion in HORIZON.</p>
      </section>
      <section name="Setup" id="Setup">
         <p>This section contains the instructions for changing the system properties for the
            runtime environment.</p>
         <p>Before building the Security API (SAPI) distribution package, the
               <i>sapi.filters.properties</i> filters properties file should be modified. Then,
            Maven will build the configuration files and scripts with the changes embedded. Those
            built configuration files and scripts will be included in the Archive distribution
            package, which is described in the <a href="../install/index.html#Distribution_Contents"
               >Distribution Contents</a> section of the <a href="../install/index.html"
               >Installation</a> document.</p>
         <p>From the top-level of the Archive program set source directory, perform the following
            command to view the current settings in the properties file:</p>
         <source>% more src/main/filters/archive.filters.properties

sapi.home=/usr/local/daac</source>
         <p>Using your favorite editor, modify the properties in the <i>sapi.filters.properties</i>
            file for the target environment referencing the following table where necessary:</p>
         <table align="center" border="1">
            <tr valign="top">
               <th align="left"><b>System Property </b></th>
               <th align="left"><b>Description</b></th>
               <th align="left"><b>Default Value</b></th>
            </tr>
            <tr valign="top">
               <td align="left">sapi.home</td>
               <td align="left">Root directory for SAPI Distribution</td>
               <td align="left">/usr/local/daac</td>
            </tr>
         </table>
         <p>Now that the properties are configured for the target environment, it is time to build
            the Security API distribution package. To verify the above setup, follow the steps in
            the <a href="../install/index.html#Setup_Verification">Setup Verification</a> section of
            the <a href="../install/index.html">Installation</a> document after the distribution
            package has been built.</p>
      </section>
      <section name="Build" id="Build">
         <p>From the top-level of the Security-API program set source directory, perform the
            following commands to clean up any artifacts and then build the Security API
            distribution package.</p>
         <source>% mvn clean
% mvn package</source>
         <p>After a successful build, the distribution package can be found in the <i>target</i>
            directory named <i>security-api-X.X.X-sapi.tar.gz</i> where <i>X.X.X</i> is the current
            version. See the <a href="../install/index.html#Distribution_Contents">Distribution
               Contents</a> section of the <a href="../install/index.html">Installation</a> document
            for a description of the distribution package contents.</p>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
