<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Copyright 2013, by the California Institute of Technology. -->
<!-- ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged. -->
<!--  -->
<!-- $Id: $ -->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
   <properties>
      <title>Release Description 5.0.0c</title>
      <author>Thomas Huang</author>
   </properties>
   <body>
      <section name="Release Description 5.0.0c">
         <p>This release of the Middleware Program Set is a component of the integrated release (<a
               href="../../cm/release/index-5.0.0c.html">5.0.0c</a>) of the HORIZON System. </p>
         <p>The Middleware Program Set is new to the HORIZON System. This program is defined to group
            all middleware-related modules for the HORIZON System. Our success in the application of
            middleware technology into the HORIZON System has demonstrated the need of more web-enable
            service components in the future of HORIZON. </p>
         <p>The first module being released with this program set is the Manager module. The Manager
            module is the successor of the ingest-grails module. Building on capabilities delivered
            in the last release, this release focuses on improving the overall reliability of the
            Middleware Services used by the HORIZON System. The service architecture offers simplified
            and flexible approach for organizing data products from various mission and/or
            instruments. </p>
         <p>The second module being released with this program set is the Inventory Web Service
            module. This module wraps the Inventory program set with a restful web service. This
            allows the Inventory program set to be separated from other modules, which increases
            security (fewer connections, usernames to the datbase) as well as flexibility (single
            point of Inventory changes, federate the inventory service). 3.2.1 is the initial
            release of the Inventory web service.</p>
         <p>Details on this release can be found in the following sections of this document:</p>
         <ul>
            <li><a href="#Capabilities">Capabilities</a></li>
            <li><a href="#System_Requirements">System Requirements</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Installation">Installation</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Operation">Operation</a></li>
         </ul>
      </section>

      <section name="Capabilities" id="Capabilities">
         <p>This section details the new, modified and corrected capabilities that comprise this
            release of the Middleware Program Set.</p>
         <subsection name="New Capabilities">
            <p>The following capabilities are new for this release</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Manager <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
               <li>SigEvent <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
               <li>Security <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>

         <subsection name="Modified Capabilities">
            <p>The following capabilities have been modified for this release</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Manager <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
               <li>SigEvent <ul>
                     <li><a href="https://bugs.earthdata.nasa.gov/browse/GIBS-198">GIBS-198</a>:
                        SigEventUI</li>
                     <li><a href="https://bugs.earthdata.nasa.gov/browse/GIBS-294">GIBS-294</a>:
                        Update SigEvent Bootstrap to load initial event categories and types.</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
               <li>Security <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>

         <subsection name="Corrected Capabilities">
            <p>The following capabilities have been corrected for this release</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Manager <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
               <li>Sigevent <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
               <li>Security <ul>
                     <li>NONE</li>
                  </ul>
               </li>
            </ul>
         </subsection>
      </section>

      <section name="System Requirements" id="System_Requirements">
         <p>The software contained in this program set was developed using Java and will run on any
            platform with a supported Java Runtime Environment (JRE). The software was specifically
            developed under Sun Java version 1.7 and has only been tested with this version.</p>
         <ul>
            <li>HORIZON Standard Computing Environment<p>This will eventually be documented on the Wiki
                  and linked to in future releases. For now, the following software and tools should
                  be available in the current environment:</p>
               <ul>
                  <li>Apache Ant 1.8.2</li>
                  <li>Apache Maven 2.2.1</li>
                  <li>Grails 2.2.4</li>
                  <li>Groovy 2.0.8</li>
                  <li>Sun Java Standard Edition (J2SE) 1.7.x</li>
               </ul>
            </li>
         </ul>
      </section>

      <section name="Installation" id="Installation">
         <p>This section details the procedures for installing and configuring the software in this
            program set.</p>
         <subsection name="Manager Installation">
            <p>The Manager module consists of the RESTful interface to the HORIZON data acquisition and
               archive service. The installation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../manager/install/index.html">Manager Installation</a> document.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="SigEvent Installation">
            <p>The SigEvent module consists of the RESTful interface to the HORIZON event publish and
               subscribe system. The installation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../sigevent/install/index.html">SigEvent Installation</a> document.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Security Installation">
            <p>The Security module consists of the RESTful interface to the HORIZON service for
               authentication and authorization system. The installation of this module is covered
               in the <a href="../security/install/index.html">Security Installation</a>
               document.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>

      <section name="Operation" id="Operation">
         <subsection name="Manager Operation">
            <p>The operation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../manager/operate/index.html">Manager Operation</a> document.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="SigEvent Operation">
            <p>The operation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../sigevent/operate/index.html">SigEvent Operation</a> document.</p>
         </subsection>
         <subsection name="Security Operation">
            <p>The operation of this module is covered in the <a
                  href="../security/operate/index.html">Security Operation</a> document.</p>
         </subsection>
      </section>

   </body>
</document>
