<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Copyright 2013, by the California Institute of Technology. -->
<!-- ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged. -->
<!--  -->
<!-- $Id: $ -->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
   <properties>
      <title>Package Release</title>
      <author>Thomas Huang</author>
   </properties>
   <body>
      <section name="Package Release">
         <p>This document details the steps necessary to build and deliver the system or a single
            program set so that it is ready for Integration &amp; Test. For general information
            regarding the use of <a href="../subversion/index.html">Subversion</a> or <a
               href="../maven/index.html">Maven</a>, see their respective documents on this site.
            The following sections can be found in this document:</p>
         <ul>
            <li><a href="#System_Release">System Release</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Program_Set_Release">Program Set Release</a></li>
         </ul>
      </section>
      <section name="System Release" id="System_Release" >
         <p>This section details the steps for performing a system release, which will probably
            consist of the release of one or more program sets which is covered in the next section.
            The first step to performing a system release is to create a tags directory in the
            Subversion repository. This can be accomplished with the following command (where X.X.X
            is the current release version):</p>
         <source>
% svn mkdir http://horizon.jpl.nasa.gov/repo/horizon/tags/X.X.X -m &quot;Release comment.&quot;
         </source>
         <p>Although it is stored in the Subversion repository like a program set, the HORIZON
            parent Project Object Model (POM) dictates the system build and defines properties that
            the program sets inherit. The parent POM can be checked out from the Subversion
            repository with the following command:</p>
         <source>
% svn checkout http://horizon/repo/trunk/horizon/trunk horizon
         </source>
         <p>Alternatively, if there is a local copy on your machine, you can perform the following
            two commands to verify that you have not made any changes to your local copy and that
            changes made by others are incorporated into your local copy:</p>
         <source>
% svn status % svn update
         </source>
         <p>The above two commands and the following commands should be executed from within the
            top-level directory of the parent POM (where the <i>pom.xml</i> file resides). Perform
            the following commands to clean old artifacts, build/deploy the current artifacts to the
            Maven repository and copy the <i>pom.xml</i> file to the tags directory for the current
            system release:</p>
         <source>
% mvn clean --non-recursive
% mvn deploy --non-recursive
% svn copy pom.xml http://horizon/repo/tags/X.X.X \ 
-m &quot;Deploy the system-level POM for system release X.X.X.&quot;
         </source>
         <p>You are now ready to prepare a program set release for each program set that makes up
            the current system release.</p>
      </section>
      <section name="Program Set Release" id="Program_Set_Release">
         <p>This section details the steps for performing a program set release. If this is part of
            a system release, then these steps will need to be performed for each program set that
            makes up the current system release. The program set can be checked out from the
            Subversion repository with the following command:</p>
         <source>
% svn checkout http://horizon/repo/trunk/&lt;program-set&gt;/trunk&lt;program-set&gt;
         </source>
         <p>Alternatively, if there is a local copy on your machine, you can perform the following
            two commands to verify that you have not made any changes to your local copy and that
            changes made by others are incorporated into your local copy:</p>
         <source>
% svn status
% svn update
         </source>
         <p>The above two commands and the following commands should be executed from within the
            top-level directory of the program set (where the <i>pom.xml</i> file resides). Perform
            the following commands to clean old artifacts and build/deploy the current artifacts to
            the Maven repository:</p>
         <source>
% mvn clean
% mvn deploy
         </source>
         <p><b>Note:</b> Current policy is that program sets only need to be deployed to the Maven
            repository if other programs sets are dependent on the artifacts.</p>
         <p>Perform the following command to deploy the site pages to the HORIZON Oceanography DAAC
            CM web site:</p>
         <source>
% mvn site-deploy
         </source>
         <p>For program sets that contain modules (e.g., Common, Ingest and Search) the following
            commands should be performed instead to deploy the site pages:</p>
         <source>
% cd util 
% ./mvn-site-deploy.sh
         </source>
         <p>Perform the following command to make a copy of the current source tree for the program
            set under the program set's tags directory (where X.X.X is the current release version
            for the program set):</p>
         <source>
% svn copy http://horizon/repo/trunk/&lt;program-set&gt;/trunk \
http://horizon/repo/trunk/&lt;program-set&gt;/tags/X.X.X \ 
-m &quot;This release of the &lt;program-set&gt; Program Set is a component of the \ 
integrated release (X.X.X) of the HORIZON System.&quot;
         </source>
         <p>Perform the following command to make a copy of the tagged program set under the system
            release's tags directory (where the first X.X.X is the program release version and the
            second X.X.X is the system release version):</p>
         <source>
% svn copy http://horizon/repo/trunk/&lt;program-set&gt;/tags/X.X.X \
http://horizon/repo/tags/X.X.X/&lt;program-set&gt; \ 
-m &quot;This release of the &lt;program-set&gt; Program Set is a component of the \ 
integrated release (X.X.X) of the HORIZON System.&quot;
         </source>
         <p>Now that you have deployed artifacts and tagged the release, the current release version
            should be bumped so that the official release does not get overwritten in the Maven
            repository by accident. This can be accomplished by editing the <i>pom.xml</i> file for
            the program set with your favorite editor. Look for the following in the <i>pom.xml</i>
            file:</p>
         <source>
...
&lt;groupId&gt;gov.nasa.horizon&lt;/groupId&gt;
&lt;artifactId&gt;&lt;program-set&gt;&lt;/artifactId&gt;
&lt;version&gt;X.X.X&lt;/version&gt;
...
         </source>
         <p>Bump the version by a point (e.g. X.X.1) and save the file. Perform the following
            command to commit the changes in the Subversion repository:</p>
         <source>
% svn commit
         </source>
         <p>Now onto the next program set if this is a system release.</p>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
