<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- Copyright 2013, by the California Institute of Technology. -->
<!-- ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. United States Government Sponsorship acknowledged. -->
<!--  -->
<!-- $Id: $ -->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
   <properties>
      <title>Operation</title>
      <author>T. Huang</author>
   </properties>
   <body>
      <section name="Operation">
         <p>This document describes how to operate the SigEvent web application. SigEvent GUI is an
            AJAX website built using the <a class="externalLink" href="http://www.dojotoolkit.com"
               >DOJO Toolkit</a>. In conjunction with the Grails server application, this graphical
            interface allows a user to operate, monitor, and maintain the SigEvent application.The
            following sections can be found in this document:</p>
         <ul>
            <li><a href="#Event_Management_Instructions">Event Management Instructions</a></li>
            <li><a href="#Category_Management_Instructions">Category Management
               Instructions</a></li>
         </ul>
      </section>
      <section name="Event_Management Instructions" id="Event_Management_Instructions">
         <p>The following are the event management operations available to a user with access to the
            site.</p>
         <ul>
            <li>View/Sort SigEvents <p>By default, all events are displayed in date descending
                  order. The menu on the left contains all the categories to filter from. Clicking a
                  column header will sort the results by that column. Click again to alternate the
                  order of sorting. The paging menu above the event list allows the traversing of
                  several event results. Hitting the refresh button will refresh the current view
                  with the latest information from the server (does not refresh the page).</p>
               <img src="../images/event-default.jpg" alt=""/>
            </li>
            <li>Search SigEvents <p>The left accordion menu has both list of categories or a search
                  form. Clicking on &quot;Search&quot; will open up the search form where the user
                  will be able to search by a range of categories. The results are instantly
                  populated in the events list to the right. Hitting &quot;Reset&quot; will clear
                  the form and resets the search results to show all events. Feature to come:
                  Searching by date/date-range.</p>
               <img src="../images/event-search.jpg" alt=""/>
            </li>
            <li>Adding a Category <p>In the category listing on the left, scrolling to the bottom of
                  the list will show a button to add a new event group category. Clicking this will
                  bring up form to create a new category/type event group.</p>
               <img src="../images/category-create.jpg" alt=""/>
            </li>
            <li>Resolving Events <p>When an event is selected, extra information is displayed in the
                  bottom right pane. In this pane, if the event has not yet been resolved, the
                  option to resolve the event will appear at the top of this pane. The user can then
                  fill out the resolution field and send a request to the server to resolve the
                  event. Resolved events will have a green box next to their listing. </p></li>
         </ul>
      </section>

      <section name="Category Management Instructions" id="Category_Management_Instructions">
         <p>The following are the category management operations available to a user with access to
            the site. To access the notification features, click on the &quot;Notifications&quot;
            tab underneath the DMAS banner. Clicking the refresh button under this tab will refresh
            the current view of notifications with the most recent server call. </p>
         <ul>
            <li>Creating a Notification <p>To create a notification, click on &quot;Create New&quot;
                  from the notification management tab. A form will open up with all the necessary
                  fields to create a new Notification. Character and input restrictions will be
                  enforced when a user begins to type in a field. Submit with &quot;Add&quot; or
                  cancel with &quot;Cancel&quot;.</p>
               <img src="../images/notification-create.jpg" alt=""/>
            </li>
            <li>Deleting a Notification<p>To delete one or many notifications, select the desired
                  notifications to delete from the notifications tab. To select many, shift click
                  through the desired notifications. Clicking on &quot;Delete Selected&quot; will
                  then attempt to remove the selected notifications. A confirmation box will appear
                  before sending the request to the server.</p>
            </li>
            <li>Editing a Notification <p>To edit a notification, double click the desired
                  notification to modify. A form will appear with editable fields similar to that of
                  the create form. Submit with &quot;Edit&quot;, cancel with &quot;Cancel&quot;.</p>
            </li>
         </ul>
      </section>
   </body>
</document>
